Finding aid for the Karl G. Yoneda papers, 1892-1998, bulk 1925-1989 LSC.1592
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 1. Communist and Labor Union Activities, 1909-1993
  - 1.4. Periodicals, 1911-1975, bulk 1925-1937
    - ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1934 January 20-December 15 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco: Rodo Shinbunsha. No. 114 (Jan. 20, 1934)-no. 140 (Dec. 15, 1934). In Japanese.
    - ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1935 January 1-November 30 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1936 January 1-May 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Duplicate Copies of: ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Nine issues of: ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco: Rodo Shinbunsha. No. 147, 150-151, 157-162. Duplicate copies. In Japanese.
    - Rodo Shimbun: English. San Francisco, California, 1934 June 25-July 20 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Rodo Shimbun: English. San Francisco: Rodo Shimbunsha. Four issues published in June 25-July 20, 1934. One issue (June 25, 1934) was published in English; the other three issues (July, 16-17, 20, 1934) in Japanese.
    - ????? Shinbun Rodosha = The Press Worker. San Francisco, California, 1933 December-1934 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      ????? Shinbun Rodosha = The Press Worker. San Francisco: Press Worker. Sixteen issues published from December, 1933 to December, 1934. In Japanese and English.
    - Eight Periodicals Published and Distributed in San Francisco, California, 1929-1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      ??·?????? Gyogyo, Kanzumegyo Rodosha = Fishermen's and Cannery Worker's Bulletin. San Francisco: Gyogyo Kyanari Rodosha Kumiai & Soko Nogyo Toitsu Iinkai = Fishermen's & Cannery Workers Industrial Union, TUUL. V. 1, no. 1 (Jan. 1, 1935). In Japanese; ???????? Insatsu Rodo Nyusu. San Francisco: Nihonjin Insatsu Rodo Kumiai. No. 1 (June 1, 1929). In Japanese; ??????????? Kokusai Rodosha Kyuenkai Shuho. San Francisco: ILD Nagura Shibu. No. 1 (Oct. 14, 1934). In Japanese; ???? Kyuen Shinbun. San Francisco: Kokusai Rodosha Yogo Domei Nihongobu. No. 1 (Aug. 1935). In Japanese; ???? Nichi-Bei Shinbun = The Japanese American News. San Francisco: Japanese American News. (Nov. 3, 1935). In English; Western Worker Special Edition. San Francisco: Western Organ of the Communist Party, USA. Apr. 10, 1933. In English and Japanese; and People's World. San Francisco: People's World. V. 1, no. 1 (Jan. 1, 1938). In English.
    - Shinbun Jugyoin Kumiai Jiho = The Union Times; Taiyo Shinposha; and Han Taiheiyo Suijo Rodosha = The Pan-Pacific Marine Worker. San Francisco, California, 1931, 1933, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Five Periodicals Published and Distributed in San Francisco, California, 1927-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - ???? Kumiai Shinbun; ????? Noen Rodosha = Agricultural Worker; and ????? Nogyo Rodosha. Sacramento, California, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      ???? Kumiai Shinbun = Kumiai Shinbun. Sacramento: C + AWIU Section Board of SACTO. V. 1, no. 1 (Nov. 15, 1933); ????? Noen Rodosha = Agricultural Worker. Sacramento: Kyanari Nogyo Rodosha Sangyo Kumiai. No. 4 (June 25, 1934)-no. 6 (Dec. 1, 1934), no. 9 (Dec., [1934?]); ????? Nogyo Rodosha = Nogyo Rodosha. Sacramento: C + AWIU Section Board of SACTO. V. 1, no. 2 (Dec. 15, 1933), v. 2, no. 5 (Mar. 15, 1934). All in Japanese.
    - ???? Kokusai Tsushin. New York, 1935-1936, unknwon (Box 4, Folder 17)
      ???? Kokusai Tsushin. New York: Kokusai Tsushin. V. 2, no. 5 (May 1935), no. [?] (Oct. 30, 1935), no. 6 (Nov. 1935), special issue (July, 1936), and no. [?] (May 193?).
    - NY?? NY Bungei. New York, 1955 May 20-1975 February (Box 5, Folder 1)
      NY?? NY Bungei. New York: N.Y. Bungei Dojinkai. No. [1] (May 20, 1957)-no. 3 (Dec., 1957), and no. 8 (Jan., 1963)-no. 11 (Feb., 1975). In Japanese.
    - ????? Rodosha Bunka; and ????? Rodosha no Chikara = The Workers' Power. New York, 1923, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Seven Periodicals Published and Distributed in New York, 1911, 1929-1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Mother Earth. New York: Mother Earth. V. 5, no. 12 (Feb., 1911). In English; ?? Feng Xian = The Chinese Vanguard. No. 85 (Jan. 15, 1933). In Chinese; ILD ???? ILD Nyusu. V. 1, no. 1. (Jan., 1933). In Japanese; ?? Kaiho. New York: Japanese Workers Association. May/June-July, 1929. In Japanese; ????? Rodosha no Koe. New York: Rodosha no Koe. May, 1934. In Japanese; and ????? Shokuryo Rodosha. New York: Japanese Group of F.W.I.U. V. 1, no. 4 (May, 1933); ?????? Tokubetsu Nyusu. Sept. 10, 1933, special issue (Apr. 25, 1934). In Japanese.
    - Nyusu = The News; Kaijo Rodo Tsushin Hokubeiban; and Rodosha no Koe. Seattle, Washington, 1930-1934, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ???? Nyusu = The News. Seattle: Nyususha. No. 4 (Jan. 1, 1938); ????????? Kaijo Rodo Tsushin Hokubeiban. Seattle: Kaitsusha. Oct. 30, 1934; ????? Rodosha no Koe. Seattle: Rodosha no Koesha. V. [1], no. [2] (Nov. 15, 1930)-no.3 (Dec. 1, 1930), v. [1], no. 5 (Jan. 15, 1931)-v. 2, no. 7 (Feb. 15, 1931), v. 2, no. 9 (Mar. 15, 1931), v. 2, no. 11 (Apr. 15, 1931), v. 2, no. 13 (June 1, 1931)-no. [15] (July 1, 1931), v. 2, no. 17 (Aug. 1, 1931). All in Japanese.
    - ???? Kaijo Tsushin; ???? Kibei Shimin = Kibei Shimin; and ?? Rodo = The Labour. Seattle, Washington, 1927, 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - ?? Haguruma. Honolulu, Hawaii, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      ?? Haguruma. Honolulu: Hawai Puroretaria Seinen Domei. No. 5 (June, 1932). In Japanese.
    - ????? Rodosha no Koe = The Voice of Labor; and ??? Shin Jidai = The Shin Jidai. Honolulu and Maui, Hawaii, 1933, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - ????? Rodosha no Koe = Workers' Voice. Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      ????? Rodosha no Koe = Workers' Voice. Vancouver, British Columbia: N.U.W.A. & L.W.I.U. Japan Section. No. 7 (June 18, 1933). In Japanese.
    - ???? Rodo Jiho = The Rodo Jiho. Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - ???? Kaiin Shinbun = The Kaiin Shimbun. Shanghai Shi, China; and ???????? Ashu Sekishoku Kaiin Shinbun. Vladivostok, Soviet Union, 1928, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - ?? Akahata. [Tokyo], Japan, 1929-1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - ?? Akahata; and ???? Akahata = Akahata. Tokyo, Japan, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      ?? Akahata. Tokyo: Akahata Shuppanbu. No. 3 (Nov. 22, 1945)-no. 4 (Nov. 29, 1945); ?? Akahata. Tokyo: Akahata Hakkojo. No. 1 (Oct. 20, 1945): ?? Akahata = Akahata. Tokyo: Akahata Henshukyoku. New ser. no. 5 (Dec. 5, 1945)-no. 9 (Jan. 1, 1946); ???? Akahata = Akahata. Tokyo: Akahata Henshukyoku. New ser. no. 10 (Jan. 8, 1946)-no. 29 (Apr. 23, 1946), new ser. no. 31 (May 6, 1946)-no. 44 (July 8, 1946). In Japanese.
    - ?? Zen'ei = The Zenei. Tokyo, Japan, 1946 February 15-May 15 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - ????? Musansha Shinbun = The Musansha Shimbun: the Proletarian News. Tokyo, Japan, 1928 September 20-1929 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      ????? Musansha Shinbun = The Musansha Shimbun: The Proletarian News. Tokyo: Musansha Shinbunsha. No. 178 (Sept. 20, 1928), no. 200 (Jan. 11, 1929)-no. 201 (Jan. 15, 1929), no. 203 (Jan. 25, 1929), no. 205 (Feb. 5, 1929), no. 210 (Mar. 6, 1929), no. 229 (June 22, 1929), no. 232 (July 11, 1929)-no. 233 (July 20, 1929). In Japanese.
    - Four Periodicals Published in Tokyo, Japan, 1928-1933 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      ??? Akai Hoshi = Akai Hoshi. Tokyo: Musansha. No. 15 (Apr. 1, 1928), no. 17 (June 1, 1928)-no. 18 (July 1, 1928), no. 20 (Sept. 1, 1928); and ???? Bungaku Shinbun = La Literatura Gazeto. Tokyo: Nihon Puroretaria Sakka Domei Shuppanbu. No. 25 (Jan. 1, 1932)-no. 26 (Jan. 15, 1932); ???? Shakai Shinbun. Tokyo: Shakai Shinbunsha. No. 33 (Jan. 21, 1933); and ?????? Rodo Nomin Shinbun. Tokyo: Rodo Nomin Shinbunsha. No. 75 (Jan. 12, 1929). In Japanese.
    - Four Periodicals Published in Tokyo, Japan, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - ???? Seinen Taishu = The Seinen Taishu; and ???? Rodo Shinbun = The Rodo Shimbun. Osaka, Japan, 1926-1933 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clippings (1 of 2), circa 1925-1926, 1929-1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      News clippings mainly from Japanese newspapers published in the United States. Includes two news clippings published in Japan, circa 1925-1926.
    - Clippings (2 of 2), 1929-1935 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Articles on communist and socialist organizations and activities from journals and miscellaneous periodicals.
    - Four Periodicals Published and Distributed in Los Angeles, California, 1933-1935, 1937 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      ????????????? Seirin Nihonjin Teien Gyosha Kumiai Geppo = The Japanese Gardener's Monthly. No. 12 (Sept. 5, 1933); ????? Noen Rodosha = The Farm Labour. V.1, no.1 (Aug. 1, 1935)-no. 2 (Sept. 1, 1935); ?????????? Nanka Gadena Renmei Geppo = The Japanese Gardeners Monthly. No. 2 (June 10, 1937), no. 4 (Aug. 10, 1937), no. 6 (Oct. 10, 1937); and ??????????? Beikoku Koyasan Daishi Kyokai Jiho = The U. S. Daishi Kyokai News. No.2 (Jan. 14, 1934).
    - ??? = Kaikyusen. San Francisco, California, 1926 September 5-1928 January 5 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      ??? Kaikyusen = Kaikyusen. San Francisco: Kaikyusensha. No. 4 (Sept. 5, 1926)-no. 18 (Jan. 5, 1928). In Japanese.
    - ?????? Zaibei Rodo Shinbun = The Japanese Worker in America. San Francisco, California, 1929 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      ?????? Zaibei Rodo Shinbun = The Japanese Worker in America. San Francisco: Zaibei Nihonjin Rodo Kyokai = Japanese Worker's Association of America. No. 7 (Mar. 5, 1929), no. 19 (Mar. 5, 1928)-no. 26 (Jan. 5, 1929), no. 28 (Apr. 4, 1929)-no. 34 (Oct. 5, 1929). In Japanese.
    - ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1935 January 1-November 30 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco: Rodo Shinbunsha. No. 141 (Jan. 1, 1935)-no. 159 (Nov. 30, 1935). In Japanese.
    - ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco, California, 1936 January 1-May 1 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      ???? Rodo Shinbun. San Francisco: Rodo Shinbunsha. No. 160 (Jan. 1, 1936)-no. 162 (Feb. 1, 1936), no. 164 (Apr. 1, 1936)-no. 165 (May 1, 1936), extra (Feb. 27, 1936). In Japanese.
    - Doho: San Francisco Supplement. San Francisco, California, 1941 December 13-22 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Doho: San Francisco Supplement. Published tri-monthly and distributed in San Francisco, California. Agent: Karl G. Yoneda; Circulation manager: Karl I. Akiya; Editor and publisher: Shuji Fujii. No. 1 (Dec. 13, 1941)-no.2 (Dec. 22, 1941). No. 1 in English only; no. 2 in English and Japanese.
    - Shinbun Jugyoin Kumiai Jiho = The Union times; Han Taiheiyo Suijo Rodosha = The Pan-Pacific Marine Worker; Taiyo Shinpo. San Francisco, California, 1931, 1933, 1937-1938 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      ????????? Shinbun Jugyoin Kumiai Jiho = The Union Times. San Francisco: Union Times. V. 1, no. 1 (Oct. 10, 1931); ????????? Han Taiheiyo Suijo Rodosha = The Pan-Pacific Marine Worker. San Francisco: International Seamen's Club. V. 2, no. 10 (June/July, 1933); and ????? Taiyo Shinposha. San Francisco: Taiyo Shinposha. V. 1, no. 1 (May 15, 1937)-no. 3 (July 30, 1937), v. 1, no. 5 (Oct. 30, 1937), and v. 2, no. 1 (Jan. 30, 1938). All in Japanese.
    - Five Periodicals Published and Distributed in San Francisco, California, 1927-1938 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      ?????? Amerika Shinbun = The America Shinbun: Japanese Weekly News. San Francisco: America Shinbun. V. 2, no. 1 (March 28, 1936); v. 3, no. 13 (May 14, 1938). In Japanese; ???? Hokubei Jiho = The Hokubei Jihoo. San Francisco: Hokubei Jihoo. V. 2, no. 3 (June 15, 1936)-no. 7 (Oct, 1936). In Japanese and English; ???????? Soko Rokyo Nyusu = Rokyo News. San Francisco: Rokyo Nyusu. No. 2 (Sept. 25, 1938), no. 3 ([193?]) In Japanese; and ???? Seinen Nippon = Seinen Nippon. San Francisco: Seinen Nippon. Special issue (Sept. 7, 1933). In Japanese; ??? Shomakyo. San Francisco: Soko Taiheiyo Birudingu. 1927. In Japanese.
    - ????? Rodosha Bunka; and ????? Rodosha no Chikara = The Workers' Power. New York, 1923, 1932-1933 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      ????? Rodosha Bunka. New York: Workers Culture. No. 1 (May 1, 1932), no. 7 (May 1, 1933). In Japanese; and ????? Rodosha no Chikara = The Workers' Power. New York: Japanese Labour Association of New York. V. 1, no. 2 (Nov. 20, 1923). In Japanese.
    - ???? Kaijo Tsushin; ???? Kibei Shimin = Kibei Shimin; and ?? Rodo = The labour. Seattle, Washington, 1927, 1934-1938 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      ???? Kaijo Tsushin. Seattle: Kaijo Tsushinsha. No. 1 (Dec. 21, 1934), no. 9 (Dec. 20, 1935), extra (1938); ???? = Kibei Shimin. Seattle: Kibei Nikkei Shimin Kyokai. V. 1, no. 3 (Mar. 1, 1934); and ?? Rodo = The Labour. Seattle: The Labour. V. 7, no. 76 (May 15, 1927), v. 7, no. 78 (July 15, 1927), v. 15, no. 217 (May 10, 1934).
    - ????? Rodosha no Koe = The Voice of Labor; and ??? Shin Jidai = The Shin Jidai. Honolulu and Maui, Hawaii, 1933, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      ????? Rodosha no Koe = The Voice of Labor. Honolulu: [The Voice of Labor]. V. 1, no. 4 (July 9, 1938)-no. 6 (July 21, 1938), v. 4, no. 1 (Nov. 10, 1938). V. 1, no. 4-6 in Japanese and v.4, no. 1 in English and Japanese; and ??? Shin Jidai = The Shin Jidai. Maui, Hawaii: The Shin Jidai. V. 3, no. 132 (Dec. 26, 1933). In Japanese.
    - ???? Rodo Jiho = The Rodo Jiho. Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      ???? Rodo Jiho = The Rodo Jiho. Vancouver, British Columbia: The Rodo Jiho. V. [1], no. 4 (Apr. 10, 1933), v. [1], no. 12 (July 30, 1933), v. [1], no. 15 (Sept. 15, 1933), extra (Sept. 15, 1933), v. [1], no. 16 (Oct. 10, 1933)-no. 18 (Nov. 25, 1933), v. 2, no. 19 (Jan. 1, 1934), v. 2, no. 21 (Feb. 15, 1934), v. 2, no. 23 (May 1, 1934)-no. 24 (June 1, 1934).
    - ???? Kaiin Shinbun = The Kaiin Shimbun. Shanghai Shi, China; and ???????? Ashu Sekishoku Kaiin Shinbun. Vladivostok, Soviet Union, 1928, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      ???? Kaiin Shinbun = The Kaiin Shimbun. Shanghai Shi: Kokusai Kaiin oyobi Kowan Rodosha Domei Taiheiyo Shokikyoku = The Organ of the Pan-Pacific Secretariat of the I. S. H. No. 32 (May 1, 1933), no. 35 (Aug. 1, 1933), no. 37 (Nov. 15, 1933); and ???????? Ashu Sekishoku Kaiin Shinbun. Vladivostok: Kokusai Kaiin Kurabu Sekishoku Rodo Kumiai Kokusai Domei = The Red Seamen of Asia International Seamen's Club. Vol. 4, no. 18 (Nov. 25, 1928). In Japanese.
    - ?? Akahata. [Tokyo], Japan, 1929-1936 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      ?? Akahata. [Tokyo]: Nihon Kyosanto. No. [1] (July 1, 1929), no. 3 (Jan. 25, 1931), no. 54 (July 15, 1932), special issue (Sept. 22, 1932), no. 100 (Oct. 5, 1932), no. 117 (Feb. 5, 1933), no. 120 (Feb. 20, 1933), and photocopies of one issue published in Aug. 1, 1936. In Japanese.
    - ?? Zen'ei = The Zenei. Tokyo, Japan, 1946 February 15-May 15 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      ?? Zen'ei = The Zenei. Tokyo: Nihon Kyosanto. V. 1, no. 1 (Feb. 15, 1946)-no. 5 (May 15, 1946). In Japanese.
    - Four Periodicals Published in Tokyo, Japan, 1930-1932 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      ???? Kyuen Shinbun. Tokyo: Kaiho Undo Giseisha Kyuenkai, Nihon Sekishoku Kyuenkai. No. 6 (Apr. 16, 1930), no. 23 (Oct. 20, 1931), extra (Oct. 28, 1932); ?????? Rokyu Nyusu. Tokyo: Nihon Rono Kyuenkai Junbikai. No. 9 (Feb. 10, 1933), extra (Mar. 15, 1933); ???????? Rono Domei Nyusu. [Tokyo]: Rono Domei Zenkoku Iinkai. No. 14 (Aug. 27, 1929); and ???????? Zenkoku Rono Taishu Shinbun. Tokyo: Zenkoku Rono Taishu Shinbunsha. No. 34 (Sept. 10, 1931). All in Japanese.
    - ???? Seinen Taishu = The Seinen Taishu; and ???? Rodo Shinbun = The Rodo Shimbun. Osaka, Japan, 1926-1933 (Box 47, Folder 17)
      ???? Seinen Taishu = The Seinen Taishu. Osaka-shi: Seinen Taishusha. No. 41 (Apr. 20, 1927)-no. 42 (July 15, 1927); ???? Rodo Shinbun = The Rodo Shimbun. Osaka- shi: Rodo Shinbunsha. No. 23 (Jan. 12, 1926), no. 67 (Oct. 25, 1932).
  - 1.5. Monographs, 1909-1911, 1925-1938, and undated
    Books and pamphlets published by communist, socialist, and other political groups in Los Angeles, San Francisco, New York, Seattle, Chicago, and Japan, between 1909 and 1911, and between 1926 and 1938, written in Japanese, English, and Esperanto. All folders are arranged by publication location.
    COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these digital materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - Monographs Published in Los Angeles, California, 1926, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      ???? Sanda, Heihachi. ???????? Shishu "Ashiato." Los Angeles: Sanda Heihachi, 1936.; Marx, Karl and Frederick Engels. ????? Kyosanto Sengen = The Communist Manifesto. Translated by ???? Kotoku Shusui, ??? Sakai Toshihiko. Los Angeles: Nihonjin Rodo Kyokai, Taisho 15 [1926]; Japanese translation of: Marx, Karl and Frederick Engels. The Communist Manifesto. [Los Angeles: s.n.]; Litvinov., M. ??????? Soren wa Tatakau ka? Los Angeles: Dohosha, 1938; Japanese translation of: Litvinov., M. Election Speech [Los Angeles: s.n.]; ??????: ????????: ?????? Beikoku Jijo Annai: Hainichi Mondai ni Tsuite: Kangei Nihon Kaigun. Los Angeles: Dohosha, 1936; ???? Kotoku, Shusui. ?????? Shakai Shugi Shinzui. [Los Angeles]: Rafu Nihonjin Rodo Kyokai, Taisho 15 [1926]; ????????????? Beikoku Kyosanto Nihongo Chuo Shokikyoku. ??????? Toyo to Sekai Heiwa. [Los Angeles]: Beikoku Kyosanto Nihongo Chuo Shokikyoku, 1937.
    - Monographs Published in San Francisco, California, 1909-1911, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      ???????? Fashizumu to Senso. San Francisco: Rodo Shinbunsha, 1934.; Workers Songs. San Francisco: Friends of the Soviet Union, [19??]; Stalin, Joseph. ?????????? Sovueto no Shinkenporon. Translated by ????? Rodosha Shobo. San Francisco: Workers Book Shop, 1937.; Kropotkin, P. ????? Seinen ni Uttau = An Appeal to the Young. Edited by ?????? Kakumei Sosho Daiichi. San Francisco: Kakumeisha, 1909; Kropotkin, Peter. ??? Kokkaron = The State: Its Historic Role. San Francisco: Beikoku Kakumeisha, 1911; Stanley. E. ????????? Museifu Shakai Shugi Genri. San Francisco: Kakumeisha, 1910.
    - Monographs Published in New York, 1930, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Stalin, Joseph. [?????????.] ??? [Renin Shugi no Kiso.] Seito hen. New York: Kokuritsusha, 1937.; Photocopies of: Specter, Frank. Story of the Imperial Valley: International Labor Defense. Pamphlet no. 3. New York: International Labor Defense, 1930; A photocopy of the cover of: ???? Hatanaka, Hideo. ????????? Nihon wa Naze Ueru? = Why Poverty in Japan? New York: Workers Library Publishers, [19??].
    - Monographs Published in Seattle, Washington, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Two pamphlets published by ?????? Taiheiyo Rodosha, Seattle, Washington, in 1935 and 1936: "??????? Furuki o Taosu Mono"; and "???????????? Kataki Akushu Zenteki Godo ni Mukatte."
    - Monographs Published in Chicago, Illinois, and Unknown, circa 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      ????????????? Minzoku, Minshu to Fashizumu Senso. Chicago: Workers Book House, 1935.; The Truth about the AFL-CIO Fight in Hawaii. [United States?: s.n., 1937-1938?]; Eronsenko, Veselj. La Gemo de Unu Soleca Animo. Sanhajo: Eldonita de Orienta Esperanto-Propaganda Instituto, 1923. In Esperanto; ????????? Moeagaru Shina Mondai. [S.l.]: Ajia Doshikai, [1936].
    - Manuscripts of a Monograh and Yoneda poetry. Japan, circa 1925-1926 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Two manuscripts: "?????? Yamamoto Kiyoshi Shohinshu," including Communist poetry compiled by Yamamato Kiyoshi, and "????????? Sanchikarizumu Kenkyu." Created in Japan.
      COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - Fifteen Monographs and Two Song Books Published in Japan, 1928-1933 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      ????????? Puroretaria Kakyokushu. Edited by ??????????? Puroretaria Ongakuka Domei. [Japan: Senkisha, 1931]; ???????? Puroretaria Kashu. [Japan: s.n.], 1932; ????? Watanabe, Masanosuke. ?????: ?·???????? Rodosha Yawa: San'ichigo Jiken Kinen Shuppan. [Japan: s.n.], 1929; ??????? Aru Heishi no Shuki. [Japan]: Tsuwamono Henshubu, 1934; ???: ????????. Eiyuron: Aru Mukishu no Tegami. Edited by ??? Kato Minoru. Osaka: Kawai Kozo Iko Kankokai, 1928; ???????? Akahata Rifuretto. [Japan]: Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai, 1932; ??????? Heishi Shokun ni Kou. [Japan]: Kokusai Kyosanto Nihon Shibu, Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai, 1932; ???????? ???????????? Kinro Fujin Ningen no Katsudo ni Okeru Wagato Tomen no Hoshin. [Japan]: Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai, 1932; ??????????? Kokusai-teki Toso Keiken kara Manabe. Edited by ?????????????????? Nihon Rodo Kumiai Zenkoku Kyogikai Chuo Jonin Iinkai. [Japan]: Nihon Rodo Kumiai Zenkoku Kyogikai, 1931; ?????? Peku Nihon Honkyoku. PEK?????????? PEK no Tadashii Ninshiki no Tame ni. Tokyo: Peku Nihon Honkyoku, 1932; ???????????? Senso to Kokusai Puroretariato. [Japan]: Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai Azipurobu, 1932; ?????????????????? Kyosanto no Borushiebiki-ka ni Kansuru Teze. [Japan: s.n.], 1932; ???? Yamamoto, Kenzo. ??????? Kaikyu-teki Rodo Kumiai. [Japan]: Zenkyo Nihon Kaiin Kowan Rodosha Kumiai Junbi Iinkai, 1933; Sokol, E. ????????????: ??????????????? Ika ni Shite Karera wa Katta ka: Waruso Shiden Jugyoin no Sutoraiki. [Japan: s.n.], 1929; ????????????????????! Zentoin wa Kyosanto Seinen Domei Kakudai Kyoka no Sento ni Tate! [Japan]: Nihon Kyosanto Kansai Chiho Iinkai, 1932; and ????????"Nihon Kyosanto Shi" [Japan]: Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai Ajipurobu, 1932.
  - 1.6. Alaskan Cannery Workers Union, 1930-1942, 1947-1989
    Contains materials regarding the Alaska Cannery Workers Union of which Yoneda was the vice president and delegate. Includes code hearing documents, scrapbooks, leaflets, bulletins, pamphlets, photographs, news clippings, and others. The materials were created and collected mainly between 1936 and 1942; other related materials were collected between 1947 and 1989.
    - Cannery Code Hearings, 1934 February 27 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      One paper binder including 115 pages of documents from the cannery code hearing held in San Francisco, California, on February 27, 1934.
    - Scrapbook: Alaska Red Salmon, 1938 June 1-August (Box 7, Folder 2)
      One scrapbook compiled by Yoneda when he was the first vice president and delegate of Diamond X Cannery, Alaska Cannery Workers Union #5, UCAPAWA-CIO, San Francisco, California. Contains news clippings, photographs, incoming letter envelopes, and the Red Salmon's canned food labels.
    - Scrapbook: Organizing Alaska Cannery Workers (1), 1913, 1934-1942, 1974-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      One scrapbook containing Yoneda's membership cards and books, photographs, an agreement between the Red Salmon Co., San Francisco, California, and their employees, the Union's election document, letters, newsletters, news clippings, and other materials issued between 1934 and 1942. There is a membership card for S. Abe issued in 1913. Also includes a copy of "Brief history of Japanese and other ethnic cannery workers in Alaska" complied by Yoneda on March 1, 1977, news clippings, and newsletters collected between 1974 and 1989.
    - Leaflets Published and Distributed by the Alaska Cannery Workers Union, #5, C.I.O., in Seattle, Washington, 1930, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Contains leaflets published and distributed by the Alaska Cannery Workers Union, #5, C.I.O., in Seattle, Washington, to the Japanese cannery workers. Includes one leaflet written by Yoneda.
    - Bulletins, Leaflets, and Pamphlet Issued by the Alaska Cannery Workers Union, Local 20195, A.F. of L., San Francisco, California, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 5)